<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>try Combine</title>
    <link>http://trycombine.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on try Combine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://trycombine.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug logging with CombinePrintout</title>
      <link>http://trycombine.com/posts/debug-logging-combineprintout/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trycombine.com/posts/debug-logging-combineprintout/</guid>
      <description>Logging is a really powerful way to debug code, especially if it&amp;rsquo;s asynchronous code that runs in a time sensitive way so stepping through the debugger is a pain.
In Simple custom Combine operators I wrote about how to create an operator that logs to the system Console app in just few lines.
After playing with Combine some more I went ahead and created a micro framework called &amp;ldquo;CombinePrintout&amp;rdquo; that adds few convenient methods to Combine allowing you to quickly print information about your subscriptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a custom `sample` operator</title>
      <link>http://trycombine.com/posts/more-simple-custom-combine-operators-with-sample/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trycombine.com/posts/more-simple-custom-combine-operators-with-sample/</guid>
      <description>In Simple custom Combine operators I spoke about how you can cheaply create your own custom Combine operator without the need to create a new custom Publisher type.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to show how this kind of &amp;ldquo;cheap&amp;rdquo; operators could actually be quite complex and useful; still being created only by creatively combining existing operators.
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at sample(_)&amp;hellip;
The sample operator rxmarbles.com is a marveleous website where you can find visual and interactive presentations of a multitude of reactive operators (based in their implementation in RxJS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple custom Combine operators</title>
      <link>http://trycombine.com/posts/simple-custom-combine-operators/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trycombine.com/posts/simple-custom-combine-operators/</guid>
      <description>Creating simple custom operators is very straightforward in Combine.
As long as your custom operator can be expressed via combining existing operators you don&amp;rsquo;t need to create a new publisher type - you can simply extend the Publisher protocol with your own custom operator.
Let&amp;rsquo;s try quickly creating one now.
Extending Publisher You can extend Publisher like any other protocol in Swift. For this post I&amp;rsquo;ll create a debugging operator that writes logs to the system console.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>