<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>actor on try Code</title>
    <link>https://trycombine.com/tags/actor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in actor on try Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trycombine.com/tags/actor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcing: “Modern Concurrency in Swift”</title>
      <link>https://trycombine.com/posts/announcing-modern-swift-concurrency-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trycombine.com/posts/announcing-modern-swift-concurrency-book/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m incredibly happy to share that today the new raywenderlich.com book &amp;ldquo;Modern Concurrency in Swift&amp;rdquo;, that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on, is available at swiftconcurrencybook.com!
Together with editors Sandra Grauschopf, Felipe Laso-Marsetti, Richard Turton, and Shai Mishali, we&amp;rsquo;ve been working very hard to get a book out as soon as possible on the newly released in 2021 Swift Concurrency:
 The book is written in the classic raywenderlich.com style that mixes key pieces of theory with step-by-step instructions, guiding the readers through working on practical, real-life projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actors, the cooperative pool and concurrency</title>
      <link>https://trycombine.com/posts/swift-actor-dispatch-queues-concurrency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trycombine.com/posts/swift-actor-dispatch-queues-concurrency/</guid>
      <description>After I started doing some benchmarking how different APIs perform, when used to build a simple counter, I got really interested to learn more about how the new Swift concurrency model behaves at runtime.
So in this post I&amp;rsquo;ll use a couple of actors and make them do concurrent computations and check how the thread list and dispatch-queues look like in the debugger.
The Test Setup I&amp;rsquo;ve prepared a super-duper simple SwiftUI app that does a bunch of floating-point multiplication and division.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance: Actor vs queue vs lock</title>
      <link>https://trycombine.com/posts/performance-actor-queue-lock-benchmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trycombine.com/posts/performance-actor-queue-lock-benchmark/</guid>
      <description>I do a lot of performance and instrumenting work and I&amp;rsquo;ve found Peter Steinberger&amp;rsquo;s post here very useful when comparing lock alternatives.
As I worked with async/await and actors more and more this summer, I thought it’d be nice to put together a short post offering some basic benchmarking of actors vs. the existing synchronization mechanisms.
Disclaimer Benchmarking depends heavily on the system, temporary conditions, and more. As with any amateur benchmarks, take the numbers in this post with a grain of salt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
