<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>markdown on try Code</title>
    <link>https://trycombine.com/tags/markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in markdown on try Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trycombine.com/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Easy app walkthroughs with MarkWalkthrough</title>
      <link>https://trycombine.com/posts/a-fun-swiftui-package-for-creating-walkthroughs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trycombine.com/posts/a-fun-swiftui-package-for-creating-walkthroughs/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago, while I was working on my app Rex Tables, I wrote some quick code that reads a Markdown file with some &amp;ldquo;slide&amp;rdquo; data and automatically displays an app walkthrough.
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t really meant for other people to use since it made use of a paid Swift package for the transition effects in the walkthrough. But that package, namely Pow, just become open sourced last week!
So I pulled the code out of Rex Tables and did a quick pass to tighten up a couple of things and pushed it to GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation tooling using MarkCodable for reports</title>
      <link>https://trycombine.com/posts/using-markcodable-to-generate-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trycombine.com/posts/using-markcodable-to-generate-reports/</guid>
      <description>For my apps dataFude for Simulator and Rex Tables I have few command line tools that run some end-to-end tests. I use MarkCodable to easily print reports to the console. In this short post I&amp;rsquo;m gonna show how MarkCodable cuts down on some of the turnaround time when I&amp;rsquo;m making tools.
MarkCodable I wrote about MarkCodable previously when I released it: Introducing MarkCodable but I wanted to give you some more examples, just for fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing MarkCodable</title>
      <link>https://trycombine.com/posts/introducing-markcodable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trycombine.com/posts/introducing-markcodable/</guid>
      <description>I had a lot of fun listening to &amp;ldquo;A releational database using Markdown&amp;rdquo; episode with John Sundell and Gui Rambo:
After taking a moment though, I started realizing that there is a whole plethora of use cases where Markdown could be a great storage for some of my data. Markdown supports tables and they are pretty easy to view, parse and edit by hand.
On the other hand, JSON isn&amp;rsquo;t very easy to view or edit by hand, which is sometimes more important for me, given I work on a lot of small tooling that automates or performs specific tasks and usually doesn&amp;rsquo;t need a large dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
