<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>development on try Code</title>
    <link>https://trycombine.com/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in development on try Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trycombine.com/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate debugging SwiftUI and UIKit with dataTile</title>
      <link>https://trycombine.com/posts/code-samples-on-how-to-approach-debugging-swift-and-uikit-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trycombine.com/posts/code-samples-on-how-to-approach-debugging-swift-and-uikit-apps/</guid>
      <description>The ability to log values and visualize them in dataTile is quite powerful, but the core concept of the app really shines when a developer automates logs that drive metrics over time.
Such metrics could be any value that changes over time, such as the size of the app cache, the amount of RAM consumed, or the number of instances created of a given class.
This article will look at two quite different approaches to tracking automation, one with SwiftUI and another with UIKit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dataTile for Simulator launches today! 🚀</title>
      <link>https://trycombine.com/posts/datatile-for-simulator-is-on-the-appstore-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trycombine.com/posts/datatile-for-simulator-is-on-the-appstore-now/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m glad to share that dataTile for Simulator is launching today on ProductHunt and the AppStore!
dataTile for Simulator is an Xcode companion app to see your debugging data in a beautiful and bold UI. Log your debug data as usual using Apple&amp;rsquo;s logging framework, and dataTile for Simulator will automatically select and display your logs!
It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful native developer tool that is focused on making developers more productive while developing with Xcode and the Simulator.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
